MOHAMED SUHAIL P.P

Suhailpp.official@gmail.com

AL-AMEEN (house), ESWARAMANGALAM (PO), TAVNOOR(via)

PONNANI, KERALA, INDIA - 679573

Mobile Number: +91 9562070176

Objective:

Psychotherapist (Psychologist) Trained and supervised in Psychodynamic Psychotherapy From

Indian Psychoanalytic Society-kolkata (2 Year Diploma In Psychiatry counseling-

Psychodynamic Psychotherapy) and Post-Graduate in Health Psychology, Also Certified in Play

Therapy .Hold more than year 4 Experience in providing Counseling and Psychotherapy. For

past 2+ years Practicing Psychotherapy (Freelance) with Supervision and Self work (Self

Therapy). My work is based in Psychodynamic Psychotherapy, along with Practicing

Psychotherapy recently Initiated to conduct training /workshop for professional who is looking

forward to Dynamic approach.

Areas/Concerns That I mostly address in Therapy are- Personality related concerns, Trauma

related Concerns, Grief Related Concerns, Abuse related Concerns and In General Mental Health

concerns though .Population that I generally see in therapy are Adult(18-65years old) and

Children (Using Play Therapy which is recently initiated). Looking forward to place my work

in a professional and wellbeing- oriented environment, would like to work towards the welfare

of fellow human beings, society and organizational goals, mean while allow myself to learn,

grow and flourish.

Professional Skills

- Trained and Supervised(On going) Psychodynamic Psychotherapy and Play Therapy
- Knowledge in administering Psychometric tests and Interventions.
- Professionally trained and skilled in counseling
- Good Presentation skills.
- Good at Communication skills Both Interpersonal and Public Speaking.
- Teaching skills in various Psychology related subjects
- Leadership and Organization skills
- Lecturing skills.
- Research skills

Professional Training

- Play Therapy workshop on 1-0-2024 to 10-04-2024 at Jolly Laha Institute Of Play
 Therapy- Kolkata
- Attended 'Online premarital counseling program' on 12,14,19&21 of October-2020.
- Attended two day online workshop on 'Arugamama & the art of psychological flexibility' on 15&16 0f May -2020
- Attended two day workshop on 'Diverse therapeutic approaches in inclusive schools',
 26& 27 Feb-2020.
- Attended two day workshop on 'Dance Movement Therapy' on 4&5 December 2019.
- Attended two day workshop on 'Cognitive Drill Therapy' on 6&7 of February 2018.
- One month Hospital of internship at Global Hospitals ,Hyderabad-India dated in between 27-07-2017 to 24-08-2017 and 16-01-2018 to 20-01-2018.
- One month Internship in psychoanalysis at Tara clinic, calicut, Kerala, India on 01-06-2017 to 30-06-2017.

Education Qualification	Institution	Percentage obtained
Post –Graduate Diploma In	Indian Psychoanalytic Society	66.37(Received Top
Psychiatry		Performer badge)
Counseling(Psychodynamic		
Psychotherapy)		
Post-Graduation (MSc-Health	University of Hyderabad-India	52
Psychology)		
Graduation (BSc Psychology)	University of Calicut, Kerala-	72
	India	
+2 (senior secondary)	MIHSS, Kerala-India	75
SSLC (10 th)	Ansar English School, Kerala-	87
	India	

Professional Experience

- Currently Part Time Psychotherapist at Tara Clinic Calicut, Kerala—(2024-April-)
- Currently Freelancing Counseling and Psychotherapy (Online) 2021- Ongoing
- Appointed as Business Development Trainee and Associate from 20-04-2021 to 09-11-2021
- Appointed as Student's Counselor(Health wellness Teacher Cum Special Educator) from 20-01-2020 to 14-01-2021 at Podar International School-Tirurapti

Professional References

- Srinvas Raju- Principal ,Podar International School-Tirupati-India Phone- +918879730476, mail- <u>principal.tirupati@podar.org</u>
- Anil Raj Hub Manager, Podar Group of schools –Bangalore Hub –India Phone- +919964742729,mail- <u>iec.anil@podar.org</u>
- Farahath K- Psychologist ,Habitat School-UAE
 Phone-056-7902005, mail-farhathfaramoideen@gmail.com

Research Experience

- Paper Publication on National Journal 'Journal Of Community Guidance & Research' on LGBT –STIGMA AND IT'S MANAGEMENT
- Conducted Research on 'Illness Adjustment and Wellbeing of person with Chronic illness'
- Conducted a Research on 'A study on Relationship Between Internet Addiction and Self-Esteem Among College Students'

Linguistic Ability

English & Malayalam Fluent in speaking, writing & Reading

Hindi & Tamil- Speaking (Able to Engage in Conversation)

Personal details

Mother's name : suharabi

Father's name : shareef P.M

Date of Birth: 09.06.1994

Marital Status : Unmarried

DECLARATION

I hereby declare that the above given details are true to the best of my knowledge.

MOHAMED SUHAIL P.P.